MICHAEL MELLO PAPERS (APAP287) 1800-2008
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Research Files, 1800-2004; 7; 14
  - "Shorter Studies: Law and Morality" by John Kuhn Bleimaier, Undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Silagy v. Peters, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Simmons v. Luebbers, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Skipper v. South Carolina, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Smith v. Bounds, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - "Social Injury Revisited: Towards a Feminist Theory of Social Justice" by Adrian Howe, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - "Social Security Benefits: The Woman's Perspective" by Linda Tarr- Whelan, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - " The Sociology of Law" by Philip Selznick, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - "Some Realism About Critical Legal Studies" by Richard Michael Fischl, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - "Some Realism about Realism- Responding to Dean Pound" by Karl N. Llewellyn, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - "Some Thoughts about Natural Law" by Phillip E. Johnson, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - "Some Thoughts on the Death of Stare Decisis in Constitutional Law" by Earl M. Maltz, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Carl Ray Songer, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Sonnier v. Maggio, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - South Dakota v. Dole, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Southern California Law Review- Articles, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - "The Spirit of Dissent" by J. Louis Campbell III, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Standards Relating to Juveniles Deliquency and Sactions - IJA- ABA Joint Commission on Juvenile Justices Standards, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Standing Alone in the Dock- Draft- A Report by the Death Penalty Information Center, ca. 1995 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Standing for First Time in US S. Ct., 1937; 1951; 1974; 1981 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Santo v. Barton, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - "Stare Decisis, Dissent, and the Background of the Justices of the Supreme Court of the United States" by John R. Schmidhouser, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - "The State as a Purveyor of Morality" by Don Welch, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - State Execution Rates as of August 11, 2003, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - State of California- Right to Serve on Jury, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Statement by the Honorable H. Lee Sarokin, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Statement of Federico M. Macias-Subcommitteee on Civil and Constitutionl Rights, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Statement of Kirk N. Bloodsworth- Subcommittee on Civil and Constitutional Rights, ca. 1993 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Statement of Justice Barkett FLSC- Hearing on Habeus Corpus Reform, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Statement of Rubin Carter- Hearing on Habeas Corpus, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Statement of Talbot D' Alemoente-Innocence and the Death Penalty, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - "The Status of Capital Punishment: A World Perspective" by Clarence H. Patrick, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Stewart v. Dugger, 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Strickland v. Washington, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Studies by Kathleen M. Heide, 1982; 1984; Undated (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - A Study of Representation of Capital Cases in Texas- The Spangenberg Group, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - "Style and Justice Holmes" by William Domnarksi, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Suarez v. Dugger, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - Submission of the National Legal Aid and Defender Association to the Ad Hoc Committee of the Judicial Conference of the United States on Federal Habeus Corpus Review in Capital Cases by Louis Bilionid, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - "Sudden Recall: Adult Memories of Child Abuse Spark a Heated Debate" by Bruce Bower, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 50)
  - Summaries of Juvenile Defendant Cases, Undated (Box 13, Folder 51)
  - Summary of Professor Yackle's Statement, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 52)
  - Summary of Remarks of Judge Donald P. Lay, Chief Judge of the 8th Circuit Court of Appeals, Undated (Box 13, Folder 53)
  - Summary of the Repor of the AD Hoc Committee on Federal Habeus Corpus in Capital Cases, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 54)
  - Summary of Statement of Davud I. Bruck, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 55)
  - "Support for the Death Penalty Remains High at 74% Slight Majority Prefers Death Penalty to Life Imprisonment as Punishment for Murder" by Jeffrey M. Jones, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 56)
  - The Supreme Court Leading Cases, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 57)
  - Supreme Court of Ohio- Report of the Committee on the Appointment of Consel For Indigent Defendants in Capital Cases, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 58)
  - "Taking Supreme Court Opinions Seriously" by Henry P. Monaghan, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 59)
  - "Taking Women as a Starting Point: Building Women's Law" by Tove Stang Dahl, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 60)
  - "The tattered Cloak of Immortality" by Audrey K. Gordon, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 61)
  - "Teaching Feminist Legal Theory at Texas, Listening to Difference and Exploring Connections" by Patricia A. Cain, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 62)
  - Teague v. Lane, 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 63)
  - "Testimony Death Penalty for Juveniles in Kentucky Concerning House Bill 392" by Victor L. Streib, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 64)
  - "Theorising about Theorising" by Dale Spender, ca.1983 (Box 13, Folder 65)
  - "The Theory of Judicial Decision" by Roscoe Pound, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 66)
  - Thomas v. Kemp, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 67)
  - Thomas v. Kemp, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 68)
  - Thompson v. Dugger, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 69)
  - "Thurgood Marshall and the Administration of Criminal Justice: An Analysis of Dissenting Opinions" by William J. Daniels, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 70)
  - "Thurgood Marshall and the Forgotten Legacy of Brown v. Board of Education: by Kenneth F. Ripple, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 71)
  - "Time and Death in Adolescence " by Rober Kastenbaum, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 72)
  - Tison v. Arizona, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 73)
  - Title M: Proceedings After Judgement Article ,440, Undated (Box 13, Folder 74)
  - Title VI, 1986-1987; Undated (Box 13, Folder 75)
  - Title VI, VII, IX Cases, 1985; 1990; 1992-1993; Undated (Box 13, Folder 76)
  - Title VI Relief from Victim- Based Discrimination in Capital Sentencing by A. Darwin Holder, Jr., 1989 (Box 13, Folder 77)
  - Toles v. Jones, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - "Too Young to Die- Juveniles and the Death Penalty- A Better Alternative to Killing Our Children: Youth Empowerment" by Sheri Jackson, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - "Toward a Theory of Law and Patriarchy" by Diane Polan, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - "Toward Neutral Principles of Constitutional Law" by Herbert Wechsler, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - "Towards a Feminist Jurisprudence" by Ann C. Scales, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - "Towards a Methodology for Feminist Research" by Maria Miles, ca. 1983 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - "Towards a Recognition of the Necessity for Defense for Politcal Protestors" by Matthew Lippman, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - "Transcendental Nonsense, Metaphoric Reasoning and the Cognitive Stakes for Law" by Steven L. Winter, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Treaty Senes- Treaties and International Agreements Registered or Filed and Recorded with the Secretariat of the United Nations, Volume 999, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - "Tribute to Justice Thurgood Marshall" by William J. Brennan, Jr., 1987 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Turner v. Florida, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Tyson v. Tyson, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - "Unconscious Racism and the Criminal Law" by Sheri Lynn Johnson, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Uniform Laws Annotated- Matrimonial, Family and Health Laws, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - United Nations- Economic and Social Council- Report on Capital Punishment, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - The United States Law Week, 1987 December 1 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - The United States Law Week, 1988 May 31 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - University of California Regents v. Bakke, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - "'Unusual' Punishment: The Domestic Effecta of International Norms Restricting the Application of the Death Penalty" by Joan F. Hartman, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - "Upon Rereading Mr.Justice Black on the First Amendment" by Harry Kalven, Jr., 1967 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - "An Urgent Plea for Help from the Alabama State Bar" by Dennis N. Balske, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - U.S. Codes, Education and Food and Drugs, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - US Supreme Court Orders, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - U.S. v. Allen, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - U.S. Jaycees v. Chicago Jr. Ass'n of Commerce, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - U.S. v. Baldi, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - U.S. v. Chandler ( 1 of 2), 1992 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - U.S. v. Chandler ( 2 0f 2), 1992 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - U.S. v. Cooper, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - U.S. v. Pretlow, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - U.S. v. Theriault, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - U.S. v. Villarreal, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - "The Value of Quantitative Methodology For Feminist Research" by Toby Epstein Jayaratne, ca. 1983 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Vesecky v. Vesecky, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - "Violence Against Women" in Ms. The World of Women, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - "Violence Juvenile Deliquents" by Lewis et al., 1979 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Virginia v. Stockton, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - "'Waiving' Goodbye to Juvenile Defendants, Getting Smart vs. Getting Tough" by Cynthia R. Noon, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - "Walking the Edge of Death: An Annotated Bibliography on Juveniles, Mentally Ill, The Mentally Retarded and the Death Penalty" by Susan M. Boland, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Wallance v. Kemp, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Walton v. Arizona, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Washington v. Davis, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Waterhouse v. Florida, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - " Ways of Criticizing the Court" by Frank H. Easterbook, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Welch v. Beto, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - "Where We Stand: Observations on the Situation of Feminist Legal Thought" by Clare Dalton, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - White v. Dugger, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - "Who Decides" by Paul Brest, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Why We Need the Great Writ: The Role of Federal Habeus Corpus in Protecting Life and Liberty by Foran et al, Undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Wilkins v. Missouri, 1987-1988 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Williams v. Lynaugh, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Williams v. Martin, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Wards Cove Packing Co., Inc. v. Atonio, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Woman's Constitution" by Kenneth L. Karst, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - "Women's Law: An Introduction to Feminist Jurisprudence" by Tove Stang Dahl, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Zeigler, Undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Subject Files, 1977-2006; 8; 1
  Series is arranged alphabetically.
  This series consists of materials related to Michael Mellos work as a professor at Vermont Law School, general correspondence, material related to Michael Mellos medical malpractice suit, and biographical material.
  - Correspondence- General, 1986-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence- General, 1991-1994; 1996-1997; 2002; 2005-2006; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Epigrams (1 of 2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Epigrams (2 of 2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Holland and Knight Invoice, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Michael Mello- Application to the Bar + DC Court of Appeals Restricted, 1984; 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Michael Mello- Malpractice Suit Against Dr. Cohen, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Michael Mello- Resume and List of Publications, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Paul Magill - Resentencing Exhibit Signed by Cast, 1987 (Oversized 1)
  - Photographs, 1977-1979; 1986; 1995; 1998-1999; 2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Vermont Law School- Capital Punishment Seminar- Materials, Volume 1 (1 of 2), Fall, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Vermont Law School- Capital Punishment Seminar- Materials, Volume 1 (2 of 2), Fall, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Vermont Law School- Capital Punishment Seminar- Materials, Volume 2 (1 of 3), Fall, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Vermont Law School- Capital Punishment Seminar- Materials, Volume 2 ( 2 of 3), Fall, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Vermont Law School- Capital Punishment Seminar- Materials, Volume 2 (3 of 3), Fall, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Vermont Law School- Lawsuit (1 of 2) RESTRICTED, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Vermont Law School- Lawsuit (2 of 2) RESTRICTED, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Vermont Law School- Presentation, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Vermont Law School- Seminar: The Death Penalty- Syllabus, Fall, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)